# ABDULLAH **ESHA**

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER



+8801521431502

shahariaresha@gmail.com



AbdullahEsha



# **SUMMARY**

I would like to work as a back-end developer and put my accumulated expertise from numerous projects and courses over the last few years to use. I am looking forward to contributing and as well as learning new technologies from time to time.



# **ACADEMIC BACKGROUND**

Bachelor Of Science in Computer Science and Engineering (CSE) | 2018 - 2021

American International University-Bangladesh

CGPA: 3.7/4.0

Higher Secondary School Certificate | 2015 - 2017

BAF Shaheen College, Dhaka 1206

GPA: 4.33/5.0



## - @ : SKILLS

Programming Language: C, C++, Java, C#, Python, JavaScript, Typescript

Frameworks: Laravel, Express.js, .NET (MVC), Next js

Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind CSS, MUI, JWT, Firebase Auth, React js, Redux,

RTK, jQuery, Ajax, JSON, and RESTful API

SQL and Database: Oracle Database, MySQL, MSSQL, MongoDB

Project deployment and version control: GitHub, Git Bash, cPanel, AWS

Project Management: Trello, GitLab

UI/UX: Figma

Office suite: Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)

Additional: Proteus, MATLAB(Simulink), WEKA Explorer, Security Onion (Linux), Postman



### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

• Junior Full-Stack Developer | May 2022- Present

SWOP Technologies, Dhaka

• Internship | Sep 2021 - Dec 2021

Atropos



## **PROJECTS**

#### Butterfly Matrimonial V2.0 (Jun 2022 - Aug 2022)

A digital platform for match-making, the main feature was generating CVs for all user as well ass analytics, search/filter in the dashboard. **React js, Redux, Laravel 9, MySql** 

#### • Qr Code Generator (Sep 2022)

A project to create or design a customizable Qr Code for any purpose. Which is fully free.

One can choose varients to create one.

React is

#### Bayshor Communication V3.0 (Feb 2023)

This website was made for a Digital marketing agency. Blogs, Services, and Plans all can be monitored from the dashboard.

\*\*Next js(Typescript), Express js, MongoDB\*\*

#### • **SWOP V2.0** (Mar 2023 - Jun 2023)

It's an NFC chip-selling platform. It also has a cross-platform app, monitored through its dashboard having JWT token validation, analytics etc. *Next js, Express js, MongoDB, Stripe* 

#### Nazaara (Jun 2023 - Present)

E-commerce website for a local company providing online service. All upload, update, delete can be performed from the admin dashboard.

\*Next js, Express js, MongoDB\*\*



## **CERTIFICATES**

#### Crash Course on Python

An online non-credit course authorized by Google and offered through Coursera - (July 2020)

### CyberOps Associate

An online course authorized by CISCO and offered by AIUB - (December 2021)

#### Paper: Assisting the Power Generation Sector Toward Sustainability-an IoT Based...

A paper published on ACM Digital Libary - (March 2022)



#### **AWARDS**

#### Dean's Award

American International University of Bangladesh - (2018)



#### **LANGUAGES**



English

Playing Football

Bengali



## **REFERENCES**

#### RAIHAN UDDIN AHMED

**Assistant Professor** 

Department of Computer Science.

ruabng2008@gmail.com

American International University Bangladesh.